[
    {
    "question": "Who is often considered the 'father of modern computer science' and a key figure in the development of the first general-purpose computer, the Analytical Engine?",
    "options": [
      "Thomas Edison",
      "Alexander Graham Bell",
      "Alan Turing",
      "Bill Gates"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "Alan Turing",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year was the first electronic digital computer, the ENIAC, completed and put into operation?",
    "options": ["1942", "1950", "1945", "1955"],
    "rightAnswer": "1945",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who co-founded Apple Inc. with Steve Jobs and is known for his contributions to the personal computer revolution?",
    "options": ["Tim Cook", "Steve Wozniak", "Mark Zuckerberg", "Jeff Bezos"],
    "rightAnswer": "Steve Wozniak",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "What technology, developed by Tim Berners-Lee in the late 1980s, revolutionized the way people access and share information on the internet?",
    "options": ["GPS", "Wi-Fi", "HTML", "Ethernet"],
    "rightAnswer": "HTML",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which computer programming language, developed by Dennis Ritchie in the early 1970s, had a significant impact on the development of operating systems and software applications?",
    "options": ["Python", "Java", "C++", "C"],
    "rightAnswer": "C",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "What event in 1969 marked the first successful message exchange between two computers on ARPANET, a precursor to the internet?",
    "options": [
      "Launch of the first satellite",
      "The moon landing",
      "Invention of the first email",
      "First internet transmission"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "First internet transmission",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company introduced the first commercially successful microcomputer, the Altair 8800, in 1975?",
    "options": ["IBM", "Microsoft", "Apple", "Intel"],
    "rightAnswer": "Apple",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for the transition from analog to digital television broadcasting that occurred in the early 2000s?",
    "options": [
      "VHS to DVD transition",
      "Digital Revolution",
      "Analog Sunset",
      "Digital TV (DTV) transition"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "Digital TV (DTV) transition",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the first web browser created by Tim Berners-Lee in 1990?",
    "options": ["Internet Explorer", "Firefox", "Mosaic", "Netscape Navigator"],
    "rightAnswer": "Mosaic",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is credited with coining the term 'artificial intelligence' and is considered one of the pioneers in the field of AI?",
    "options": ["John McCarthy", "Elon Musk", "Mark Zuckerberg", "Larry Page"],
    "rightAnswer": "John McCarthy",
    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What does CPU stand for?",

    "options": [
      "Central Processing Unit",

      "Computer Processing Unit",

      "Central Processor Unit",

      "Computer Processor Unit"
    ],

    "rightAnswer": "Central Processing Unit",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which programming language is often used for web development and is known for its client-side scripting capabilities?",

    "options": ["Java", "Python", "JavaScript", "C#"],

    "rightAnswer": "JavaScript",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the binary representation of the decimal number 25?",

    "options": ["11001", "10001", "10101", "11101"],

    "rightAnswer": "11001",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What data structure follows the 'Last-In, First-Out' (LIFO) principle?",

    "options": ["Queue", "Stack", "Linked List", "Array"],

    "rightAnswer": "Stack",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a type of loop structure in programming?",

    "options": ["for loop", "if-else loop", "while loop", "do-while loop"],

    "rightAnswer": "if-else loop",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of a database management system (DBMS)?",

    "options": [
      "To store and manage data",

      "To display data on a website",

      "To create user interfaces",

      "To design computer networks"
    ],

    "rightAnswer": "To store and manage data",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What does HTML stand for?",

    "options": [
      "HyperText Markup Language",

      "Hyperlink and Text Markup Language",

      "High-Level Text Markup Language",

      "HyperTransfer Markup Language"
    ],

    "rightAnswer": "HyperText Markup Language",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which data type is used to store whole numbers in many programming languages?",

    "options": ["Float", "Double", "Integer", "Character"],

    "rightAnswer": "Integer",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which data structure is used to store a collection of elements with no specific order and no duplicate values?",

    "options": ["Array", "Linked List", "Set", "Stack"],

    "rightAnswer": "Set",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "In binary code, what does the digit '1' represent?",

    "options": ["On", "Off", "Both On and Off", "Neither On nor Off"],

    "rightAnswer": "On",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which programming language is often used for data analysis, machine learning, and scientific computing?",

    "options": ["C++", "Ruby", "Java", "Python"],

    "rightAnswer": "Python",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the term for a variable that is accessible and usable throughout an entire program?",

    "options": [
      "Local variable",

      "Global variable",

      "Constant variable",

      "Static variable"
    ],

    "rightAnswer": "Global variable",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a valid programming paradigm?",

    "options": [
      "Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)",

      "Functional Programming (FP)",

      "Spaghetti Programming (SP)",

      "Procedural Programming (PP)"
    ],

    "rightAnswer": "Spaghetti Programming (SP)",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What does the acronym HTTP stand for in the context of web communication?",

    "options": [
      "Hyper Transfer Text Protocol",

      "Hyperlink and Text Transfer Protocol",

      "Hypertext Transfer Protocol",

      "High-Level Text Transmission Protocol"
    ],

    "rightAnswer": "Hypertext Transfer Protocol",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What does the acronym IDE stand for in the context of software development?",

    "options": [
      "Integrated Development Environment",

      "Internet Development Environment",

      "Interactive Design Environment",

      "Intelligent Debugging Environment"
    ],

    "rightAnswer": "Integrated Development Environment",

    "questionType": "text"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a 'break' statement in programming?",
    "options": [
      "To end a loop prematurely and exit the loop",
      "To create a loop",
      "To define functions",
      "To execute a block of code repeatedly"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "To end a loop prematurely and exit the loop",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sorting algorithm has an average time complexity of O(n*log(n)), making it efficient for large datasets?",
    "options": [
      "Bubble Sort",
      "Insertion Sort",
      "Quick Sort",
      "Selection Sort"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "Quick Sort",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "In binary code, what does the combination '1010' represent?",
    "options": ["7", "10", "5", "3"],
    "rightAnswer": "10",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which programming language is commonly used for game development and is known for its performance and graphics capabilities?",
    "options": ["Java", "Python", "C++", "Ruby"],
    "rightAnswer": "C++",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term 'API' stand for in computer programming?",
    "options": [
      "Application Programming Interface",
      "Advanced Programming Interface",
      "Automated Programming Interface",
      "Application Process Integration"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "Application Programming Interface",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which data structure stores elements in a first-in, first-out (FIFO) order?",
    "options": ["Queue", "Stack", "Linked List", "Array"],
    "rightAnswer": "Queue",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "In web development, what does the acronym 'HTTP' stand for?",
    "options": [
      "Hyper Transfer Text Protocol",
      "Hyperlink and Text Transfer Protocol",
      "Hypertext Transfer Protocol",
      "High-Level Text Transmission Protocol"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "Hypertext Transfer Protocol",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of a 'function' in programming?",
    "options": [
      "To define variables",
      "To create loops",
      "To execute a block of code repeatedly",
      "To encapsulate a block of code for reuse"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "To encapsulate a block of code for reuse",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term 'OOP' stand for in programming?",
    "options": [
      "Object-Oriented Programming",
      "Object-Oriented Protocol",
      "Object-Oriented Process",
      "Object-Oriented Parser"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "Object-Oriented Programming",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which data structure uses the 'FILO' (First-In, Last-Out) principle?",
    "options": ["Queue", "Stack", "Linked List", "Array"],
    "rightAnswer": "Stack",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "In binary code, what does the combination '0011' represent?",
    "options": ["1", "3", "4", "6"],
    "rightAnswer": "3",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which programming language is commonly used for scientific computing and data analysis?",
    "options": ["Java", "Python", "C++", "Ruby"],
    "rightAnswer": "Python",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term 'URL' stand for in web addresses?",
    "options": [
      "Universal Resource Locator",
      "Uniform Resource Link",
      "Unique Resource Locator",
      "Universal Reference Link"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "Universal Resource Locator",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which data structure stores elements in a way that resembles a real-world line or queue?",
    "options": ["Queue", "Stack", "Linked List", "Array"],
    "rightAnswer": "Queue",
    "questionType": "text"
  },
  {
    "question": "In web development, what does the acronym 'CSS' stand for?",
    "options": [
      "Computer Style Sheets",
      "Creative Style Sheets",
      "Cascading Style Sheets",
      "Content Style Sheets"
    ],
    "rightAnswer": "Cascading Style Sheets",
    "questionType": "text"
  }
]